hi there I'm Luis Gomez with palo alto
你好， 我是路易斯·戈麦斯和帕洛阿尔托
education and i'd like to teach you how
教育，我想教你如何
to make your very own
做你自己的
rock-paper-scissors plain program using
使用石头剪刀平原程序
machine learning so this is gonna be a
机器学习所以这将是一个
very fun project and we're gonna learn a
非常有趣的项目，我们将学习一个
ton about the fundamentals of machine
关于机器的基本原理
learning so why rock paper scissors
学习所以为什么摇滚纸剪刀
well humans aren't that great at it
以及人类是不是在它那大
I mean seriously so what I'm envisioning
我的意思是认真的，所以我想象的是什么
is a program that can do a little bit
是一个可以做一点点的程序
better than this
比这更好
so something more along these lines
所以更多的东西沿着这些方向
that's what I'm talking about you know
这就是我所说的你知道的
bring on anybody bring on the rock paper
带上任何人带来的摇滚纸
scissors world champion we can take him
剪刀世界冠军我们可以带他
on no problem with this program that
在这个程序中没有问题
we're gonna build so how do we do this
我们要建造所以我们如何做到这一点
well let's let's think a little bit
好，让我们，让我们觉得有点
let's start breaking it down a little
让我们开始分解一下
bit thinking about what our goals for
有点想我们 的目标是什么
this program should be so obviously
这个程序应该是如此明显
someone cuz I know someone's going to
某人因为我知道有人要去
come up to the computer show Rock and
来到电脑秀Rock和
the computer is going to return paper
电脑将要归还纸张
somebody's going to come up to the
有人会来
computer show the paper shape and the
计算机显示纸张的形状和
computer is going to return scissors you
电脑会把剪刀还给你
get the idea but the biggest problem
得到的想法， 但最大的问题
here is get the computer to recognize
这是让计算机识别
images how how can we do that you know
想象一下 你怎么知道我们怎么做
how can we teach a computer to recognize
我们怎样才能教电脑识别
shapes and images how can we how can we
形状和图像我们怎样才能
do that how was it possible how can a
这样做怎么可能怎么样？
computer understand something how can it
电脑了解一些事情怎么可能
get the idea of something so we're gonna
得到一些东西的想法， 所以我们会
use a very common thing that we use in
使用我们使用 了一个非常平常的事
machine learning called training data so
机器学习叫做训练数据
this is a super key concept for machine
这是机器的超级关键概念
learning it's having a lot of training
学习它有很多的培训
data today we're gonna be using images
今天的数据我们将使用图像
because rock paper scissors is obviously
因为岩石剪刀很明显
an image based a visual based game so
基于视觉的游戏的图像
for example one piece of training data
例如一条训练数据
we might have is a picture of somebody
我们可能有某人的照片
doing the rock symbol and a label this
做岩石符号和标签，这
is very important with training data
是训练数据很重要
each piece of data also has to come with
每个数据也必须随附
its own label so we take this image of
它自己的标签，所以我们采取这种形象
rock we take our label that says rock
摇滚，我们把我们的标签，上面写着岩
literally
按照字面
just the word rock and we're gonna pass
只是摇滚这个词，我们会过去的
this into our machine learning model and
这进入我们的机器学习模型和
we want to get a bunch of these okay we
我们希望得到一堆 这些好我们的
want one for each label we're gonna have
想要一个我们将拥有的每个标签
three labels because there's three
三个标签，因为有三个
possible outcomes in rock-paper-scissors
岩纸剪刀可能产生的结果
well three possible moves I should say
我应该说三个可能的举动
in rock-paper-scissors you've got
你用的是石头剪刀
rock-paper-scissors
剪刀石头布
so we want to make sure we get plenty of
所以我们要确保我们得到充足的
images for each of these three labels so
这三个标签中的每一个的图像都是如此
image of paper make sure we label it
纸张图像确保我们标记它
paper hand it off to the computer
纸把它交给电脑
another image of rock label at rock hand
岩石标签的另一个图象在岩石手的
it off to the computer image of scissors
其关闭，以剪刀的计算机图像
label at scissors pass it off to the
剪刀上的标签将它传递给了
computer and so on so we're gonna keep
电脑等所以我们要保持
doing this over and over and over again
这样做一遍又一遍又一遍
and the more training data we get and
以及我们得到的更多训练数据
the more varied it looks the better our
看起来越多样我们就越好
model is going to perform in an actual
模型将在实际中执行
game of rock-paper-scissors and we'll
我们会用石头剪刀游戏
talk a little bit more about that later
稍后再谈一点
but let's start getting into this
但是让我们开始讨论这个问题
project and setting everything up so we
项目和设置一切， 所以我们
can right away just start writing down
可以马上开始写下来
some code so let's get started we're
一些代码让我们开始吧
gonna open up a new browser tab and
打开一个新的浏览器选项卡和
we're gonna go to machine learning for
我们要去机器学习的
kids code UK you can just search machine
孩子们代码英国你可以只搜索机器
learning for kids into Google or
为孩子们学习Google或Google
whatever and the website will come up so
无论和网站会想出如此
we're gonna click on worksheets here and
我们要在这里点击工作表
we're gonna scroll down till we see our
我们要向下滚动， 直到看到我们的
projects should be right here rock paper
项目应该在这里摇滚纸
scissors and click on download where a
剪刀，然后点击下载
student so we're gonna click download
学生，所以我们要点击下载
project two worksheet let that download
项目两个工作表让下载
and while that's happening we're gonna
而那时我们会发生这种情况
go over here click log in okay now I've
走在这里点击登录还好现在我已经
got the worksheet pulled up already and
得到了工作拉升已经和
this is exactly what the worksheet says
这正是工作表所说的
to do so I'm just walking you through
这样做我只是带你走过
this worksheet already if you want to
如果你愿意，这个工作表已经
pull it up and follow along we're just
把它拉起来跟着我们走
gonna be walking through this so click
将要点击这一点
on login I'm gonna log in real quick and
在登录我要登录 真正的快速和
we're gonna go to your projects so let's
我们要去你的项目所以让我们
add a new project and we're gonna title
添加一个新项目，我们将获得冠军
it
它
paper scissors and recognizing like we
剪刀和像我们一样认识
said the type of data we're going to be
说我们将要的数据类型
using is images so make sure to click
使用是图像， 所以一定要点击
images right here and click create
图像就在这里，然后单击创建
and there's our project so they're gonna
而且我们的项目就是他们要去的
open that up just click on that go to
打开它只需点击即可
Train click this little train button
火车点击这个小火车按钮
right here so right here see this button
就在这里， 所以在这里看到这个按钮
where it says add new label like we said
它说像我们说的那样添加新标签
earlier we're gonna want three labels
早些时候我们要三个标签
rock-paper-scissors we'll just start off
我们刚刚开始使用石头剪刀
with one so let's click add new label
用一个让我们点击添加新标签
and we're gonna write Rock and add so
我们要写Rock并添加
there's that and since we want to you
就是这样，因为我们想要你
know we want it to play against real
知道我们希望它与真实对抗
humans okay we want to get somebody
人类好我们想得到一个人
sitting next to us to play against our
坐在我们旁边与我们对抗
program and have our program kick their
计划并让我们的计划踢他们的
butt so we want to take pictures
对接所以我们想拍照
ourselves of rock paper scissors so
我们自己用石头剪刀这样
we're gonna click on webcam you might
我们可能会点击网络摄像头
get something up here asking you to
得到的东西在这里问你
allow access to your webcam just click
只需点击即可访问您的网络摄像头
allow and because I'm recording my
允许，因为我正在录制我的
screen right now I'm not able to use my
屏幕现在我无法使用我的
webcam but you will be able to just
网络摄像头，但你可以只是
follow along with this worksheet right
请跟随这个工作权
here click webcam click allow we just
点击网络摄像头点击允许我们
did that and now you're gonna click this
做到了，现在你要点击这个
Add button right here ok and you know
在这里添加按钮 确定，你知道
make your make your hand into a fist
让你的手握成拳头
shape for Rock and click Add and just
Rock的形状， 然后单击Add and just
fill this up take like ten pictures of
填补这一走起来像拍摄10张照片
rock and I'm gonna go do that real quick
摇滚，我要快点去做那件事
and I'll be right back alright so
我会马上回来好吧
hopefully you've got all your rock
希望你有你所有的摇滚乐
images let's add a new label now of
图片让我们现在添加一个新标签
paper I'm gonna click add and click on
纸我要点击添加然后点击
webcam over here and ah there I am so
摄像头在这里啊，我就是这样
you know what to do you know what to do
你知道该怎么做你知道该怎么做
make the paper symbol hold it up to your
使纸符号支持你的
webcam at different angles use a
不同角度的网络摄像头使用
different hand you know yeah so we're
不同的手，你知道是的，所以我们
gonna take ten pick
要拿十挑
of the paper symbol and we're gonna come
纸质符号，我们会来的
back we're gonna do the same exact thing
回来我们会做同样的事情
with the scissors but so let's get let's
用剪刀但是让我们放手吧
get ten pictures of paper great so
得到十张纸很棒的照片
you've got your ten images of rock maybe
你有十张摇滚影像可能
you've got more if you do that's awesome
如果你这样做的话，你会得到更多
at least ten images of paper and we're
至少十张纸的图像，我们是
gonna add a new label here type in
这里要添加一个新标签
scissors and if you spell it wrong you
剪刀，如果你拼写错了你
can just come up here delete it click
可以来这里删除它点击
yes try again so we're gonna add a new
是的再试一次，所以我们要添加一个新的
label of scissors
剪刀的标签
boom ad boom click on webcam boom you
热潮广告热潮点击网络摄像头热潮你
know what to do scissors from different
知道从不同的剪刀做什么
angles different hands different
角度不同的手不同
rotations so if we take a picture of
旋转，所以如果我们采取的图片
some things face or like a desk or a
有些东西面对或像桌子或桌子
crayon or something I don't know and we
蜡笔或我不知道的东西和我们
label it as scissors our computer is
将它标记为我们的电脑剪刀
gonna think that's what scissors look
会想到这就是剪刀的样子
like and we don't want that so if you
喜欢和我们不希望如此，如果你
take a picture of something other than
拍一张照片以外的东西
scissors on accident click that little
事故上的剪刀点击那个小
red X there get rid of it and that takes
红色X摆脱它，这需要
care of that so yeah I'll just get ten
照顾那么，是的，我只会十点
at least ten of scissors and different
至少十把剪刀和不同
rotations get that done and we'll be
轮换完成了，我们将成为
right back
马上回来
great so we've got all the images that
太棒了所以我们得到了所有的图像
we need now all we're gonna do is back
我们现在需要做的就是回来
out of here click on back to project go
离开这里点击返回项目去
to learn and test so this is going to be
学习和测试所以这将是
where we actually feed all of the images
我们实际上提供所有图像的地方
and labels that we created into our
而我们到创建的标签我们
machine learning model so it can start
机器学习模型，所以它可以开始
learning and getting an idea of what
学习并了解什么
rock paper and scissors all mean so to
摇滚纸和剪刀都是这样的意思
do that we're just gonna click this one
那样做我们只是点击这个
symbol button here train your machine
这里的符号按钮训练你的机器
learning model and there we go so
学习模式，我们走这样
training will take awhile and even
培训需要一段时间甚至是
though we've only got around 30 pictures
虽然我们只有大约30张照片
or so it'll still take a while because
或者它还需要一段时间，因为
there's a lot of complicated math
有很多复杂的数学
happening in the background right now
现在在后台发生
the math and algorithms behind what
什么背后的数学和算法
we're doing right now aren't so
我们正在做的， 现在不那么
important as the high-level ideas
重要的是高层次的想法
the idea of having training data
有训练数据的想法
associated with labels and passing this
与标签相关联并传递此信息
off to a model and letting it do all of
关闭模型并让它完成所有工作
the complicated math for us and getting
在复杂的数学为我们和获取
an idea of what each of our labels means
什么 我们每一个标签是指 一个想法
or in this case what each of our labels
或者在这种情况下我们的每个标签
will look like oh great
看起来很棒哦
looks like our model is done training
看起来我们的模型已经完成了培训
pool so our model is ready to test oh
游泳池， 所以我们的模型准备测试哦
man this is exciting isn't it I'm
人这是令人兴奋的是不是我
excited I actually haven't tested it yet
兴奋我实际上还没有测试过它
so this is gonna be my first time seeing
所以这会是我第一次看到
it to pop up in the webcam oh let's see
它会弹出网络摄像头哦让我们看看
Wow
哇
with only 10 I'm actually astounded by
只有10只我真的很震惊
that 276 is good now that our models in
那个276现在好我们的模特了
training let's continue with this
训练让我们继续这个
worksheet great so we've now got our
工作表很棒，所以我们现在得到了我们的
trained model we're gonna make the final
训练有素的模特我们要进入决赛
logic for our rock-paper-scissors robot
我们的摇滚剪刀机器人的逻辑
to beat any human even the
甚至击败任何人
rock-paper-scissors world champ we're
我们是摇滚纸剪刀世界冠军
gonna do that right now so let's scroll
现在就这样做， 让我们滚动吧
up right here click back to project and
在这里点击返回项目和
we are gonna open scratch I'm gonna
我们要打开我要去的地方
click this open and scratch button oh I
点击这个打开和刮开按钮哦我
need flash you might need to enable this
需要闪存你可能需要启用它
as well give this one second to load
加载这一秒钟
cool so now that we've got scratch open
现在我们已经开始刮了
we're just gonna follow along with this
我们要跟着这个
worksheet make sure we've got some
工作表确保我们有一些
blocks right here which we do we've got
我们在这里阻挡了我们所拥有的
rock paper scissors and recognize image
岩石剪刀和识别图像
cool so if you've got some extra blocks
如果你有一些额外的块，那就太酷了
there don't worry about it's not going
不用担心它不会发生
to be an issue as long as we've got rock
只要我们有摇滚乐 就成为一个问题
paper scissors and recognized image
剪刀和公认的图像
label blocks we'll be good so go over
标签块我们会很好，所以过去
here to project templates and look for
这里是项目模板和寻找
rock paper scissors sweet alright so now
摇滚纸剪刀现在很好
that we've got scratch open we're just
我们已经开放了，我们只是
gonna follow the instructions on the
要遵循的说明
worksheet nice and simple
工作表很好，很简单
so pay
所以付钱
mention to what the blocks are doing
提到块正在做什么
think through as you're reading the
当你正在阅读时，请仔细思考
worksheet what each block you're putting
工作表你正在放置的每个块
down is is happy is doing so we're gonna
我很高兴这是我们要做的
code this up real quick so I'll coat
快速编码，这样我就会外套
this up I won't show you step by step
这一点我不会一步一步给你看
how to do it I'll leave some of that
怎么做我会留下一些
exploration to you a little out of focus
探索你有点失焦
there there we go
那里我们去
and yeah just to get you started you're
是的， 只是为了让你开始吧
gonna want to go over to the results
想要回到结果
sprite just like it says right here so
精灵就像它说的那样
you're gonna click on result go up here
你要点击结果就在这里
to events to find this color of block
到事件找到这种颜色的块
that says when I receive and just drop
当我收到并且放弃时说
it in right here
就在这里
let's fullscreen this so you can see
让我们全屏看看你可以看到
better when I receive you're gonna click
当我收到你的时候会更好点击
this drop-down click score and that's
这个下拉点击分数就是这样
how you get that block that's the basic
你如何得到该块这是最基本的
idea of scratch
划痕的想法
so yeah just match up the colors match
所以， 只是匹配颜色匹配
up the different blocks and if you need
不同的块，如果你需要的话
help with the colors ask a friend or ask
帮助颜色问朋友或询问
your teacher but yeah I'll let you code
你的老师，但是我会让你编码
this up and I'll be right back with all
这了，我马上就回来了所有
of the code complete alright so
代码完全没问题
hopefully you've got all that code down
希望你已经完成了所有代码
we're gonna continue following along
我们要继续跟进
with the worksheet and click on the you
使用工作表并单击您
sprite which is down here click on you
在这里的精灵点击你
and just check real quick yeah we're
并且检查真正的快速是的我们是
gonna click on the costumes tab and
要点击服装标签和
let's do a new costume and we're gonna
让我们做一个新的服装，我们会
do new costume from camera and this is
从相机做新的服装，这是
let's click allow' on this allow again
让我们点击'允许'再次允许这个
and this is going to be the move that we
这将是我们的举动
present the our AI with our machine
用我们的机器展示我们的AI
learning robot with so let's take a
这样学习机器人让我们拿一个
picture of I'll do scissors doesn't
我会做剪刀的图片没有
matter do whatever move you want
做任何你想要的动作
whatever you think you can you can win
无论你怎么想，你都能赢
with all right let's take this scissors
好吧，让我们拿这把剪刀
picture
图片
all right so I got my scissors picture
好吧所以我得到了我的剪刀图片
we're gonna keep following along to do
我们会继续跟进去做
click on the scripts tab and we're gonna
点击脚本标签，我们就会
finish up some final code blocks here
在这里完成一些最终的代码块
and we'll be ready to go up against our
我们将准备去对付我们的
super smart trained machine learning
超级智能训练机器学习
model right here Oh back to the scripts
模特就在这里哦回到剧本
tab and we are just going to add the
选项卡，我们只是要添加
following script blocks so I'm gonna add
以下脚本块所以我要添加
some code blocks in real quick I'll let
一些代码块真的很快我会让
you do that at your own pace I'm gonna
你按照自己的节奏做到这一点我会
pause the video real quick and do that
快速暂停视频并执行此操作
and I'll be right back
我会马上回来
all right that one was much easier than
好吧，一个比一个容易得多
the first set of code blocks we had to
我们必须使用的第一组代码块
add so now we're just going to make sure
现在添加，我们只是要确定
to save our project go to file save
保存我们的项目转到文件保存
project just save our project somewhere
项目只是保存我们的项目
easy to reach like the Downloads folder
像Downloads文件夹一样容易到达
call it rock-paper-scissors
叫它摇滚纸剪刀
a default name is fine cool so we've now
一个默认名称很酷，所以我们现在
saved our scratch file which is
保存了我们的临时文件
connected to our machine learning model
连接到我们的机器学习模型
and now it's time to test let's see how
现在是时候测试让我们看看如何
well that our model can play against a
以及我们的模型可以对抗一个
real-life human so all we're gonna do is
真实的人类， 所以我们要做的就是
click go and that's it this is gonna be
点击去，这就是它
this is the final test let's see let's
这是最后的测试让我们看看吧
see how well our computer performs gets
看看我们的电脑表现得如何
the real human being three two one
真正的人是三两一个
he's cheating he's cheating
他在欺骗他的作弊行为
he's definitely cheating I don't believe
他绝对是在欺骗我不相信
that for one second
那一秒
reset reset
重置重置
alright I'm just I'm just messing around
好吧，我只是在搞乱
now but you can see it's recognizing
现在， 但你可以看到它的认识
scissors like we we confirmed that
剪刀就像我们确认的那样
earlier that it was recognizing so when
早些时候它正在认识到这一点
we did the little scissors test so it's
我们做了小剪刀测试，所以它
working you've got your rock paper
工作你有你的摇滚纸
scissors about here and if you want to
剪刀在这里，如果你想
change the computer settings okay yeah
更改计算机设置好吧是啊
it's actually picking so the codes
它实际上是在挑选代码
actually picking random between rock
实际上在摇滚之间随意挑选
paper and scissors we can make it so
纸和剪刀，我们可以做到这一点
that the computer wins every time
计算机每次都赢
but you know this is good enough to show
但是你知道这很好展示
us how the machine learning model works
我们机器学习模型是如何工作的
so remember the big idea behind all of
所以请记住所有背后的重要思想
this pull the worksheet back up is we
这拉工作表备份是我们
had training data with labels we passed
有我们通过的标签的培训数据
this training data and the labels into
将此培训数据和标签放入
our machine learning model it gathered
我们收集的机器学习模型
information about each piece of training
有关每段训练信息
data so for all of the data that was
所有数据的数据都是如此
labeled Rock our model learned different
标记Rock我们的模型学到了不同
curves different lines different colors
曲线不同线条不同的颜色
different shapes for rock did the same
岩石的 不同形状也是如此
thing for paper and for scissors and now
纸和剪刀的东西现在
it's using that to recognize scissors
它用它来识别剪刀
right here boom just pretty cool so
这里的繁荣只是很酷所以
that's the rock paper scissors project I
那是我的石头剪刀项目
hope you enjoyed it and I hope you keep
希望你喜欢它，我希望你保持
reading and learning more about machine
阅读和学习更多关于机器的知识
learning and completing more of these
学习并完成更多这些
projects because they're super fun
项目， 因为他们非常有趣